<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://robdoesdata.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://robdoesdata.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2024-10-23T22:24:09+00:00</updated><id>https://robdoesdata.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Why use Drawio in data engineering?</title><link href="https://robdoesdata.github.io/blog/2024/why-use-drawio-in-data-engineering/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why use Drawio in data engineering?"/><published>2024-05-06T22:32:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-05-06T22:32:00+00:00</updated><id>https://robdoesdata.github.io/blog/2024/why-use-drawio-in-data-engineering</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://robdoesdata.github.io/blog/2024/why-use-drawio-in-data-engineering/"><![CDATA[]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html">What roles exist in the modern data team?</title><link href="https://robdoesdata.github.io/blog/2024/what-roles-exist-in-the-modern-data-team/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What roles exist in the modern data team?"/><published>2024-03-09T23:45:34+00:00</published><updated>2024-03-09T23:45:34+00:00</updated><id>https://robdoesdata.github.io/blog/2024/what-roles-exist-in-the-modern-data-team</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://robdoesdata.github.io/blog/2024/what-roles-exist-in-the-modern-data-team/"><![CDATA[]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html">Who is RobDoesData?</title><link href="https://robdoesdata.github.io/blog/2015/robdoesdata-introduction/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Who is RobDoesData?"/><published>2015-05-15T21:01:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-05-15T21:01:00+00:00</updated><id>https://robdoesdata.github.io/blog/2015/robdoesdata-introduction</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://robdoesdata.github.io/blog/2015/robdoesdata-introduction/"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/assets/img/blogs/2024-02-26-robdoesdata.png" width="900"/></p> <h1 id="about-me">About me!</h1> <p>Hi, I’m Rob (also known as @RobDoesData) and this is my first blog post! I am currently working in the UK defence sector in the fuzzy overlapping zone of data engineering and data analytics. I specialise in developing proof-of-concept demonstrations covering all aspects of data and AI by using a combination of Python, PowerBI, and most recently, Microsoft Azure. Before this I worked in academia where my research focused on geophysical and astrophysical fluid dynamics, more specifically developing simulations of Earth’s core.</p> <h1 id="where-did-it-all-begin">Where did it all begin?</h1> <p>Back in my school days, I was just never really that into it and left school when I was a teenager with no qualifications. When I was around 16 I decided to go back into education to obtain my GCSEs at the local college and this is where I found my passion for maths and problem solving. Fast forward 6 years and I had completed my GCSEs, my A-levels, a Bachelor’s degree in Applied Maths and Theoretical Physics, and was just starting an integrated Masters and Ph.D. in Fluid Dynamics. For my master’s project, I investigated flood management by combining a tabletop demonstration model with a numerical algorithm I had developed to describe river flow. I used the demonstration at various public outreach events to engage and educate the general public on the science of extreme weather events and flooding. During my PhD work, I got to run supercomputer simulations solving the equations describing fluid flow and publish my work in leading academic journals. As an added bonus, I got to travel all over the world presenting my work at conferences, spent a summer as a visiting researcher at UCLA, and won a prestigious presentation award in San Francisco. I am very passionate about science communication and have been involved in various outreach events in which I took technical concepts and made them accessible to a general audience.</p> <table> <thead> <tr> <th style="text-align: center"><img src="/assets/img/blogs/robdoesdata-intro.png" width="600" alt=""/></th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td style="text-align: center">(left) Me with my rotating convection experiment <em>Calimero</em> at UCLA. (right) Internationally invited speakers for the IPGP conference in Paris</td> </tr> </tbody> </table> <h1 id="so-how-did-i-get-into-data">So how did I get into data?</h1> <p>Post covid, I didn’t know what I was going to do for work but knew that it was time to go into industry. While I hadn’t had any formal education in computer science, I had been responsible for managing my own data during my academic research (at the time I didn’t know what ETL was but I had been doing it) and built my own machine learning and data visualisation tools in Python. Data science and data engineering seemed like a logical fit so I took the plunge and just a year later I am leading small teams of data analysts. I have had a blast over the last year, rapidly developing my knowledge of databases, AI, and cloud/platform engineering.</p> <h1 id="why-did-i-start-this-blog">Why did I start this blog?</h1> <p>My journey to becoming a data professional is quite unique and I often approach things differently to my peers. I think there may be value in sharing my thoughts on various topics covering data and AI as I do have a different view and approach to problem-solving. It may take a while for me to find my blogging style but I hope you bear with me! Hopefully, you will find some of my future posts of interest and engaging enough to contact me!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[this is what included images could look like]]></summary></entry></feed>